Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/yannlecun-0b999 (LinkedIn) yann.lecun.com (Personal) www.cs.nyu.edu/~yann (Company)

Top Skills

Research machine learning computer vision

Publications

Classification of patterns of EEG synchronization for seizure prediction

Predictive network modeling of the high-resolution dynamic plant transcriptome in response to nitrate

Moving Beyond Feature Design: Deep Architectures and Automatic Feature Learning in Music Informatics

Comparing SVM and convolutional networks for epileptic seizure prediction from intracranial EEG

Feature Learning and Deep Architectures: New Directions for Music Informatics

Yann LeCun

VP & Chief Al Scientist at Facebook New York

Summary

Professor, researcher, and R&D manager with academic and industry experience in AI, machine learning, deep learning, computer vision, intelligent data analysis, data mining, data compression, digital library systems, and robotics.

Specialties: research, technical consulting, scientific advising.

Experience

Facebook

6 years 9 months

VP & Chief Al Scientist

March 2018 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Greater New York City Area

Scientific and technical leadership at Facebook Al Research, Al R&D strategy.

Director of AI Research

December 2013 - February 2018 (4 years 3 months)

Greater New York City Area

Director of Facebook AI Research (FAIR), with research locations in Menlo Park, New York City, and Paris, focused on bringing about major advances in AI.

Professor at NYU on a part-time basis (since January 2014).

Cofounder and advisor of Elements Inc. (biometrics), and Museami (music technology)

New York University

Professor

September 2003 - Present (17 years)

Silver Professor of Computer Science, Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences (since 2006)

Professor of Neural Science, NYU Center for Neural Science (since 2007)

Page 1 of 3

Professor of Electrical and Computer Engineering, NYU School of Engineering (since 2011)

Professor of Data Science, NYU Center for Data Science (since 2013) Founding Director of the NYU Center for Data Science (since 2013)

Research and teaching in machine learning, AI, data science, computer vision, robotics, computational neuroscience, and knowledge extraction from data,

Element Inc Co-founder, Advisor July 2012 - Present (8 years 2 months)

New York City

Elements develops software-based biometric authentication technology.

MuseAmi Cofounder and Chief Scientist 2007 - 2016 (9 years) Greater New York City Area

Development of innovative software and hardware technology for, music production, music education, and musical entertainment. Products includes mobile apps such as Improvox, Hook'd and MusicPal.

YLC Consulting LLC

Owner

January 2008 - December 2013 (6 years)

Research, Development, and Technology Consulting in software, machine learning, machine vision, robotics, data mining, data modeling, statistical data analysis, OCR, data compression, music technology and related topics.

NEC Research Institute

Fellow

January 2002 - August 2003 (1 year 8 months)

Princeton, NJ

Research in machine learning and computer vision.

AT&T Labs Research
Department Head
January 1996 - January 2002 (6 years 1 month)
Middletown, NJ

Head of the Image Processing Research Department.

Directed research in machine learning, pattern recognition, image compression, video compression, animated characters. Department members included Yoshua Bengio, Leon Bottou, Eric Cosatto, Hans-Peter Graf, Patrick Haffner, Fu Jie Huang, Jörn Ostermann, Patrice Simard, Vladimir Vapnik,

AT&T Bell Laboratories

8 years

research staff member October 1988 - January 1996 (7 years 4 months) Holmdel, NJ

Carried out research in machine learning, neural nets, optical character recognition, handwriting recognition, signature verification, integrated circuits for pattern recognition, and other topics.

Research Staff Member 1988 - 1996 (8 years)

Research staff member 1988 - 1996 (8 years)

THALES - Laboratoire Central de Recherche research scientist 1991 - 1991 (less than a year)

University of Toronto
Research Associate (postdoc)
1987 - 1988 (1 year)
postdoc in the Geoff Hinton's lab in the Department of Computer Science.

Education

Pierre and Marie Curie University PhD, Computer Science (1983 - 1987)

ESIEE PARIS

Engineering Diploma, Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (1978 - 1983)